#### Contact

stephaniep2226@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ stephaniebetances (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Human Resources
Strategic Planning
Business Partner Support

## Languages

Spanish Italian

### Certifications

Project management
Certificate of Human Resources
SHRM-CP
Human Resources Management

Honors-Awards
Cum Lade

# Stephanie Betances, SHRM-CP

Multi-Industry experienced Human Resources Director focused on impact and building social value for tomorrows workplace Englewood, New Jersey

# Summary

Strategic leader with successful record of partnering with C-Suite and other executives to enhance human capital and operational excellence.

Multi-Functional expertise in Human Resources Business Partner, Compensation and Benefits, Mergers and Acquisitions, Reorganizations and HR operations Role.

Driving implementation of Strategic Competence development plans and promoting different modes of learning and different learning solutions;

In-depth experience in large scale change management. Driving and promoting company's culture and values;

Specialties: Learning & Development, Change Management, Labor Law, Coaching, Leadership Development, Organization design, analytics and metrics design.

# Experience

StructureTech New York, Inc Human Resources Director July 2018 - Present Mount Vernon, New York

Consolidated HR functions previously managed by several different departments.

Developed organization strategies by identifying human resources issues; contributing information, analysis, and recommendations to organization strategic thinking and direction; establishing human resources objectives in line with organizational objectives.

Implemented human resources strategies by establishing department accountability, counting talent acquisition, staffing, employment processing, compensation, health and welfare benefits, training and development, records management, safety and health, succession planning, employee relations and retention, AA/EEO compliance, and labor relations.

Managed human resources operations by recruiting, selecting, orienting, training, coaching, counseling, and disciplining staff; planning, monitoring, appraising, and reviewing staff job contributions; maintaining compensation; determining production, productivity, quality, and customer-service strategies; designing systems; accumulating resources; resolving problems; implementing change during period of high growth.

Developed human resources operations financial strategies by estimating, forecasting, and anticipating requirements, trends, and variances; aligning monetary resources; developing action plans; measuring and analyzing results; initiating corrective actions; minimizing the impact of variances.

Accomplished special project results by iclarifying issues and priorities; communicating and coordinating requirements; expediting fulfillment; evaluating milestone accomplishments; changing assumptions and direction.

Introduced metrics-based performance management system with a heavy emphasis on operating results. Spearheaded value-add employee recognition and awards programs.

Guided Executive leadership and employee actions by researching, creating, writing, and updating policies, procedures, methods, and guidelines; communicating and enforcing organization values.

Bright Beginnings South Florida, Inc. Human Resources Consultant August 2012 - Present

Miami/Fort Lauderdale Area

Advising management on the administration of human resources policies and procedures

Serving as internal consultants by analyzing a company's current HR programs and recommending solutions

Developing, revising, and implementing HR policies and procedures

Ensuring HR programs and services are in compliance with established policies and procedures and state/federal laws and regulations

Preparing and maintaining reports related to specific HR projects

Assisting with the development and coordination of recommended changes regarding workflow

Developing methods for compiling and analyzing data for reports and special projects

Conducting audits of HR activities to ensure compliance
Presenting training sessions related to specific HR programs

#### **EHS**

Human Resources Director August 2016 - July 2018 (2 years) New Jersey

- Transitioned HR from traditional labor relations function into comprehensive HR organization focused on best-in-class HR policies, HRIS technology, staff and management training, and support of strategic business goals. 1 direct report.
- Consulted with business in the design and delivery of HR solutions on a broad spectrum of HR matters, including associate relations, recruiting, performance management and talent development
- Provided strategic thought, leadership, education, and tools to managers and associates on the application of company policies, procedures, and effectively managing change and transition.
- Coached and supported managers in increasing high performing teams, building talent bench, and driving associate engagement.
- Developed new hire orientation program; including a revised employee handbook ensuring consistency and minimizing exposure to liability.
- Provided HR leadership during a period of rapid growth with better than 18% increase in annual revenues and 10% gain in profitability. Currently supporting initial efforts to establish secondary trucking facility to meet customer needs.
- Enhanced organizational learning and development by facilitating training programs and group discussions on various topic, leadership development, change management, performance management.
- Administered all State and federal mandated personnel training.
- Administered all employee benefits and oversee employee eligibility.
- Captured \$50K in benefit cost reductions and avoided an additional \$800K in retirement plan funding Create talent management plans to align with a shortand long-term strategic plans
- Worker's compensation and General Liability manager

Cablevision Systems
Sr HR Coordinator
July 2008 - August 2016 (8 years 2 months)

- Provide administrative assistance to the Area Operations Manager of Construction
- Responsible for day-to-day issues related to the goals and objectives of the Department
- Prepare reports and documents in a proficient manner while verifying accuracy of content
- Research and maintain information for routine reports and special assignments, Organize and maintain confidential files
- Perform various administrative duties such as compiling timesheets, receiving and routing incoming mail, typing correspondence, filing, and maintaining stationary and reorder supplies
- Utilize and perform data entry into the Engineering Tracking System (ETS)
   and Outside Plant Tracking Systems to track all construction activity

The Coca-Cola Company
Sr. Coordintor
July 2006 - July 2008 (2 years 1 month)
Greater New York City Area

Chase
Bank Teller
January 2006 - October 2006 (10 months)
Greater New York City Area

# EXPRESS Sales Associate

January 2004 - January 2006 (2 years 1 month) Greater New York City Area

Hermanas Mirabal Family Center Human Resources Coordinator January 2002 - December 2004 (3 years) Bronx, NY

Lover Me Tender Prechsool Human Resources Intern January 2001 - 2002 (2 years) Riverdale, NY

# Education

Pace University

Master's degree, Human Resources Management/Personnel Administration, General  $\cdot$  (2018 - 2020)

John Jay College of Criminal Justice
Bachelor's degree, Forensic Psychology · (2012 - 2015)